League of Women Voters of Albany County; Records apap128
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Administrative Files, 1940-2001; 1; 3.1 cubic ft.
  - Budget Committee, 1999 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 23)
  - By-laws, 1940-1991 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 24)
  - By-laws, Amendments, 1961-1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 25)
  - By-laws, LWVNYS, 1940-1977 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 26)
  - By-laws, LWVUS, 1960-1988 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 27)
  - Calendars of Activities, 1958-1980 (not inclusive) (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 28)
  - Finance Drive, 1943-1962 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 29)
  - Finance Drive, 1965-1980 (not inclusive) (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 30)
  - Finance Drive, 1982 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 31)
  - Finance Drive, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 32)
  - Financing the League, 1965; 1967-1969; 1972-1976 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 33)
  - Grassroots Network Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 34)
  - "Handbook for League Leaders", LWVAC, Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 35)
  - Inter League Organization Minutes, 1975-1986 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 36)
  - Leagues of the Capital District, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 37)
  - Leagues of New York State, 1964-1965; 1973-1977 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - League Organization, 1982; 1988; 1992; 1994-1995 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Managing Material, 1998 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Member Handbooks, 1964; 1975-1977 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Member Mentoring Program, 1997 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Membership Campaign, 1940-1960 (not inclusive) (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Membership Campaign, 1971-1984 (not inclusive) (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Membership Campaign, 1993-1997 (not inclusive) (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Membership Committee, LWVNYS, 1975-1977 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
  - Membership Committee Interest Sheets, 1985-1987 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
  - Membership Committee Interest Sheets, 1998 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Membership Directories, 1970-1971; 1983-1986; 1988-1989 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
  - Membership Directories, 1990-1993; 1995-1996 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - Membership Guides, 1953; 1960; 1968; 1975; 1978 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
  - Membership Lists, 1943-1949 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
  - Membership Lists, 1950-1959 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 16)
    (missing 1953, 1954).
  - Membership Lists, 1961-1962; 1964; 1966-1967; 1969 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - Membership Lists, 1970-1982 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
    (missing 1973, 1976).
  - Membership Pamphlets, 1964; 1970 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Nominations Committee, 1995-1998 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 20)
  - Organization Committee, 1969; 1974-1977 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 21)
  - Policies, 1982-1983; 1990-1991 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 22)
  - President's Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 23)
  - President's Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 24)
  - President's Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 25)
  - President's Correspondence, 1980; 1988; 1990-1995 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 26)
  - President's Correspondence, 1996 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 27)
  - President's Correspondence, 1997 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 28)
  - President's Correspondence, 1998 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 29)
  - President's Correspondence, 1999; 2001 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 30)
  - President's Packet, 1986 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 31)
  - The Way to Get Involved, Brochures, 1993-2000 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 32)
  - Brochures, 1965-1999 (Box 39 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1940-1942 (Box 39 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Membership Bulletins, 1942-1944 (Box 39 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
- Voter Service, 1945-2000; 2; 2.79 cubic ft.
  Series 2 contains materials related to Voter Service, the LWVAC's most active program. Voter Service materials include information about the activities the LWVAC took part in such as registering people to vote, participating in poll watching during elections, sponsoring debates and publishing pamphlets with information about candidates and citizens' voting rights. In this particular collection there are several bulletins on "Voter Service and Election Law", campaign material for the Motor Voter Law in the United States in 1990 and in New York State in 1994, campaign material for Permanent Personal Registration in New York State, and the Get Out the Vote Campaign of 1996. Published material includes Voter's Guides from various years and Your City, County and Political Parties (no date). Also in this series are papers from the Speaker's Bureau (1961-1990, not inclusive), the LWVAC committee that spoke to other local groups informing them about voting procedures and upcoming elections.
  - Advocate for the Voter, 1989 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 1)
  - Albany City School Board Election, Candidate Questionnaires, 1971 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 2)
  - Albany City School Board Election Study, 1987-1995 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 3)
  - Albany Housing Authority Tennant Commission Election, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 4)
  - Albany Housing Authority Tennant Commission Election, Election Rules, Volunteer Instructions and Election Materials, 1978 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 5)
  - Albany Housing Authority Tennant Commission Election, News Clippings, 1976-1978 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 6)
  - Albany County Opportunity, Inc. Election, Correspondence and Meeting Notes, 1978 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 7)
  - Ballot Access, 1991 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 8)
  - Brochures and Flyers, LWVAC, 1968; 1970 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 9)
  - Brochures and Flyers, LWVNYS, 1972; 1977; 1979 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 10)
  - Brochures and Flyers, LWVUS, 1968 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 11)
  - Brochures and Flyers, Other Organizations, Undated (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 12)
  - Bulletins on Voter Service and Election Law, LWVNYS, 1968-1984 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 13)
  - Bulletins on Voter Service and Election Law, LWVNYS, 1972-1977 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 14)
  - Bulletins on Voter Service and Election Law, LWVNYS, 1978-1980 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 15)
  - Bulletins on Voter Service and Election Law, LWVNYS, 1981-1986 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 16)
  - Bulletins on Voter Service and Election Law, LWVNYS, 1990-1991 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 17)
  - Campaign Watch, LWVUS, 1992 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 18)
  - Candidate Forum Sponsored by LWVAC, 1973; 1976-1979; 1982; 2000 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 19)
  - Congressional Interviews with Representative Michael McNulty, 1995-1996 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 20)
  - Congressional Roll Call Votes, Correspondence, Permanent Personal Registration, 1966-1968 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 21)
  - Correspondence regarding Series for The Albany Liberator on Albany's Inner City and Registration, 1967 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 22)
  - Debates, Presidential Debates, 1980; 1988 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 23)
  - Debates, Senatorial Debate, LWVNYS, 1980 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 24)
  - Debates, Sponsored Debates, LWVAC, 1996-1997 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 25)
  - Don't Read This, Pamphlet Project, LWVAC, 1975-1977 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 26)
  - Elections, Election Procedures in New York State, LWVNYS, 1972 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 27)
  - Elections, Election Law, Grand Jury Hearing of James Ryan II, 1973 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 28)
  - Election Law, Legislation, 1989 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 29)
  - Election Law, News Clippings, 1978-1994 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 30)
  - Election Law, Study of Election Law and Procedures, 1972-1975 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 31)
  - Election Law, Study of Election Law and Procedure and Campaign Financing in Albany County, 1989-1991 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 32)
  - Election Law/Campaign Finance, Surveys and Results, and NYSLWV Board Leader's Guides, 1990-1991 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 33)
  - Electoral College, Correspondence and News Clippings, 1979-1980; 1992 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 34)
  - Facts for Voters, LWVNYS, 1945; 1947; 1949; 1952-1958 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 35)
  - Facts for Voters, LWVNYS, 1959-1969 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 36)
  - Facts for Voters, LWVNYS, 1970-1973; 1975-1978; 1981; 1983; 1985-1987 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 37)
  - Facts for Voters, LWVNYS, 1989-1993; 1996-1998 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 38)
  - Facts for Voters, Election Inspectors, and Election Monitors, LWVAC, 1975 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 39)
  - Filling the Vacancy in NYS Legislature, Correspondence, 1979-1980; 1991 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 40)
  - Get Out the Vote, Campaign Kit, LWVUS, 1996 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 41)
  - Get Out the Vote, Training Conference, LWVUS, 1996 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 42)
  - Get Out the Vote, Campaign, LWVUS, 1996 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 43)
  - Guide to Voters Service, LWVNYS, 1981 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 44)
  - Making Democracy Work Program, LWVUS, 1995-1996 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 45)
  - Making Democracy Work Program, LWVUS, 1996-1998 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 46)
  - Manual of Election Law for Citizens and Poll Watchers, LWVAC, 1977 (Box 4 (2-Voter Service), Folder 47)
  - Motor Voter Laws, 1990; 1994 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 1)
    Motor Voter Law, LWVUS, 1990; Motor Voter Law, LWVNYS, 1994.
  - Motor Voter Law, News Clippings, 1990-1996 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 2)
  - National Voter Registration Day, 1988 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 3)
  - New York State Board of Elections, Brochures Election System, Undated (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 4)
  - New York State Board of Elections, 1993 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 5)
  - Permanent Personal Registration, 1946; 1951-1954 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 6)
    Campaign, 1946; League Activities for PPR, 1951-1954.
  - Permanent Personal Registration, 1954-1962 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 7)
    League statements about the Optional Law, 1954; Voting Workshop, 1962; League Activities, 1954-1962.
  - Permanent Personal Registration, 1951; 1954 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 8)
    Report to Governor Thomas E. Dewey on Permanent Personal Registration of Electors, by Robert F. Ray, 1952; Model Voter Registration System, 1954; Chapter 531, New York State Optional Law, 1954.
  - Political Party and Candidate Questionnaires, Congressional Roll Call Votes, 1964-1965 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 9)
  - Polling Place Accessibility Survey, LWVAC, 1984 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 10)
  - Polling Places and Procedures, 1973; 1975; 1977; 1980-1982 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 11)
  - Poll Watcher's Checklists, 1975; 1978 (Box 5 (2-Voter Service), Folder 12)
    General Elections, 1975, Election Inspection Handbook, 1978.
  - Poll Watching on Primary Day in the 2nd Ward of the City of Albany, LWVAC, 1989 (Box 6 (2-Voter Service), Folder 1)
  - Power the Vote Coalition, LWVAC, 1996-1997 (Box 6 (2-Voter Service), Folder 2)
  - Power the Vote Coalition Meetings, LWVAC, 1996 (Box 6 (2-Voter Service), Folder 3)
  - Power the Vote Coalition Correspondence and the Women's Vote Project, 1996 (Box 6 (2-Voter Service), Folder 4)
  - Power the Vote, Proposal for Power the Vote, LWVAC, 1996 (Box 6 (2-Voter Service), Folder 5)
  - Power the Vote, Publicity and Final Report, 1996 (Box 6 (2-Voter Service), Folder 6)
  - Pre-Session Interviews with New York State Legislators, LWVAC, 1979-1985 (Box 6 (2-Voter Service), Folder 7)
  - Primaries, Brochures and Correspondence, 1953; 1980 (Box 6 (2-Voter Service), Folder 8)
  - Project Positive Campaigning, 1996 (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 1)
  - Registration and Political Party Organization, 1960-1963 (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 2)
  - Registration and Voting Procedures in New York State, 1985; Undated (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 3)
  - Southwest Voter Registration Education Project, LWVUS, 1996 (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 4)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1961-1966 (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 5)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1967-1968 (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 6)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1969-1973 (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 7)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1974-1979 (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 8)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1980-1983; 1985; 1990 (Box 7 (2-Voter Service), Folder 9)
  - Unit Presentation on Voters Service, 1977 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 1)
  - Universal Voter Registration Act, 1977 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 2)
  - Voters' Guide, 1954-1957; 1959-1961 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 3)
  - Voter's Guides in Knickerbocker News, 1962 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 4)
  - Voter's Guides by Other Organizations, 1966-1967; 1994 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 5)
  - Voter's Guides, Correspondence and Candidates Questionnaires, 1972-1978 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 6)
  - Voter's Guides, Candidate Questionnaires, 1977-1979 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 7)
  - Voters Have Pull, Pamphlet Project, 1985 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 8)
  - Voting Machine Correspondence and Pamphlets, 1963-1967 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 9)
  - Voter and Registration Guides by Other Leagues, 1972-1973; 1975; 1979 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 10)
  - Voter Registration and Voter Education, 1977-1979 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 11)
  - Voter Registration Drive, Bosnian Refugees, 1998 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 12)
  - Voter Registration Drive Correspondence, 1972-1973; 1976; 1981; 1984 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 13)
  - Voter Registration, News Clippings, 1990-1997 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 14)
  - Voter Registration Packet, Pamphlets, Poster, Brochures, 1990 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 15)
  - Voter Registration, Telephone Service Logs, 1977-1978 (Box 8 (2-Voter Service), Folder 16)
  - Voter Services, Board Reports and Correspondence, 1974-1983 (Box 9 (2-Voter Service), Folder 1)
  - Voter Services, Correspondence, 1981-1982; 1997 (Box 9 (2-Voter Service), Folder 2)
  - Voter Services, 1966-1973 (Box 9 (2-Voter Service), Folder 3)
    High School Registration Program Correspondence, Lists of Eligible Students, Notes and News Clippings with Attatched Letters, 1978-1981; Nursing Home Registration, Correspondence, 1979-1980; Upper Hudson Library Foundation Registration, 1977-1978, 1981.
  - Voter Service Handbooks, LWVUS, Registration Procedures, LWVUS, 1968-1973 (Box 9 (2-Voter Service), Folder 4)
  - Voter Services, Voter Participation, News Clippings, 1974; 1976; 1981-1982; 1989 (Box 9 (2-Voter Service), Folder 5)
  - Who Represents You, Pamphlets, 1981; 1993-1997 (Box 9 (2-Voter Service), Folder 6)
  - Women's Participation in Political Campaigns Workshop, 1977 (Box 9 (2-Voter Service), Folder 7)
  - Election Law, 1980-1996 (Box 39 (2-Voter Service), Folder 4)
  - Elections, Civil Action, 1965 (Box 39 (2-Voter Service), Folder 5)
  - Elections, LWVNYS, Primaries, 1960 (Box 39 (2-Voter Service), Folder 6)
  - Elections, Special Election for Albany Housing Authority Tenant Commissioner, 1978 (Box 39 (2-Voter Service), Folder 7)
  - Permanent Personal Registration, Undated (Oversized 3)
  - Power the Vote, Posters, 1996 (Oversized 3)
  - Voters' Guide, 1967-1971 (Oversized 3)
- Local Program Studies, 1948-1999; 3; 2.69 cubic ft.
  Local Program Studies are studies and projects done by the LWVAC that concerned the local area and its citizens. The group evaluated such things as the mental health facilities (beginning in 1954), housing (1969 and 1973), and the civic center in Albany County (1984-1985). The Observer Corps (1982-1987), an LWVAC committee, observed meetings of the local governments to monitor compliance of those governments with the New York State Open Meeting Law and Freedom of Information Law following an Open Meeting Survey conducted by the group in 1980. Other local items of study included redistricting the city and county of Albany (1964-1967), solid waste management and the use of the ANSWERS incineration plant (1989-1991), and household hazardous material. From the latter study the LWVAC produced Household Hazards: A Guide to Detoxifying Your Home in 1988 and 1990, which is in this series rather than with publications in Series 7.
  - Your City, County and Political Parties, LWVAC, Undated (Box 9 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 8)
  - Albany County Civic Center Study, 1984 (Box 9 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 9)
  - Albany County Civic Center, Study, 1984 (Box 9 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 10)
    (including an outline for the Draft Environmental Impact Statement).
  - Albany County Civic Center, Study, Executive Summary, 1984-1985 (Box 9 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 11)
    (including the Draft Environmental Impact Statement).
  - Albany County Civic Center, News Clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 9 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 12)
  - Albany County Mental Health Study, 1955-1957 (Box 9 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 13)
  - Albany County Mental Health, New York State Legislative Acts and Community Programs, 1954; 1956-1957 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 1)
  - Albany County Mental Health, Study, 1958-1961 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 2)
  - Albany County Mental Health, Study, 1966-1968 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 3)
  - Albany County Mental Health Board, 1964-1966 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 4)
    Annual Report, 1964; Study of the Albany Child Guidance Center for Psychiatric Service, Inc., 1966.
  - Albany County Mental Health, Study, News Clippings, 1958-1968 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 5)
  - Albany County Mental Health, Study, 1978-1979 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 6)
  - Albany County Mental Health, Study, 1988-1989 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 7)
  - Albany County Mental Health, Study, 1989 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 8)
  - Albany County Mental Health, Committee, 1991-1995 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 9)
  - Albany County Mental Health, Brochures and New Clippings, 1955; 1960; 1968; 1976-1978 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 10)
  - Albany County Mental Health, Publications, 1988 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 11-12)
  - Albany Housing Authority, 1986-1988 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 13)
  - Albany Public Schools Board of Education, 1989 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 14)
  - Board of Cooperative Educational Services (BOCES), Correspondence and Brochures, 1972-1973 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 15)
  - Civilian Review Board of Albany City Police, 1999 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 16)
  - Community Service Board, Mental Health Information, Open Government Information, 1979 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 17)
  - Development of Human Resources in Albany County, 1964-1967 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 18)
  - Financing Education Consensus, Undated (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 19)
  - Financing Education, Real Property Tax Study, 1977-1979 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 20)
  - Financing Education, Real Property Tax Study, 1979-1980 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 21)
  - Financing Education, Real Property Tax Study, 1981-1982 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 22)
  - Financing Education, The Fiscal Policy Institution, Information, Undated (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 23)
  - Hazardous Waste Study and Forum Sponsored by LWVAC, 1982-1986 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 24)
  - Household Hazards: A Guide to Detoxifying Your Home by LWVAC, 1988; 1990 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 25-26)
  - Housing in Albany County Study, 1969; 1973 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 27)
  - Know Your Schools Study, 1949 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 28)
  - Know Your Town Study, 1973-1975 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 29)
    Bethlehem, 1973 and Guilderland, 1975.
  - Land Use Study by Inter League Organization, 1973-1979 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 30)
  - Land Use Study, Open Space, 1991 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 31)
  - Land Use Study, Pine Bush, 1978-1979 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 32)
  - Land Use Study, Pine Bush, 1994; 1995 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 33)
  - Local Program Items, 1969-1972 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 34)
    (including Albany County Charter).
  - Local Program Items, 1976-1979 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 35)
    (including Albany School Board, Housing, Bethlehem Land Use, and Election Law).
  - Local Program Items, 1994-1998 (Box 10 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 36)
    (including Albany County Charter Revision and Regionalization).
  - Observer Corps, 1982-1984 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 1)
  - Observer Corps, 1985-1987 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 2)
  - Open Meeting Law, Correspondence, 1979; 1983-1986 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 3)
  - Open Meeting Law, News Clippings, 1978-1986 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 4)
  - Open Meeting Law, Report of New York Department of State Committee on Open Government to New York State Government and Legislature, 1985 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 5)
  - Open Meeting Survey, 1980-1981 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 6)
  - Open Occupancy Study, 1961-1963 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 7)
  - Pesticides, Bethlehem, 1998 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 8)
  - Reapportionment Albany, Correspondence, 1965-1990 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 9)
  - Reapportionment Albany, News Clippings, 1980 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 10)
  - Redistricting Study, Correspondence, Notes, Ward Maps, Senate Act, Voters' Guide, 1964-1966 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 11)
  - Redistricting, News Clippings, 1965-1967; 1973 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 12)
  - Redistricting, News Clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 13)
  - Redistricting, Official Canvass of the County of Albany Election, 1965 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 14)
  - Redistricting the City and County of Albany Study, 1964 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 15)
  - Redistricting the City and County of Albany Study, 1964-1966 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 16)
  - Redistricting and Reapportionment, Reports, 1964-1969 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 17)
  - Regionalization in the Capital District, 1994 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 18)
  - Regionalization in the Capital District, 1994-1996 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 19)
  - Regionalization in the Capital District, 1996 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 20)
  - Solid Waste Management, Composting Study, 1989-1991 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 21)
  - Solid Waste Management, Five League Study, 1990-1992 (Box 11 (3-Local Program Studies), Folder 22)